Finding aid to Out But Not Down Club Records CA.MS.00314
Smith College Archives
Out But Not Down Club Records
1952-1998
Smith College Archives
Out But Not Down Club
CA.MS.00314
0.833 linear feet (2 containers)
The records contain minutes, photographs, newspaper clippings, meeting minutes, membership directories, and reunion materials documenting the Out But Not Down Club's activities.
Biographical / Historical
The Out But Not Down Club (OBND) was the generous innovation created by Albert Blakeslee, Professor of Botany and Director of the Smith College Genetics Experiment Station, 1942-1954. When his wife Margaret Blakeslee died in 1947 he donated money to the college to create a memorial fund in her honor called "An Investment in Friendship." The memorial fund supports the activities of the OBND Club which primarily consist of several dinners each year featuring speakers on a wide variety of topics. Members of the Smith College faculty and administration who plan to continue living in the Northampton area are eligible for membership when they retire.
Scope and Contents
The records of the club consist of memos, correspondence, photographs, treasurer's reports, meeting minutes, invitations, financial records, newsletters, officers lists, CVs of members, mailing lists, speeches, and information about the various speakers over the years.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for use without restriction beyond the standard terms and conditions of Smith College Special Collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records of the Out But Not Down Club have been donated over the years by the secretary of the club at the time.
- Records, 1952-53 (Box 646, Folder 1)
- Records, 1953-54 (Box 646, Folder 2)
- Records, 1954-55 (Box 646, Folder 3)
- Records, 1955-56 (Box 646, Folder 4)
- Records, 1956-57 (Box 646, Folder 5)
- Records, 1957-58 (Box 646, Folder 6)
- Records, 1958-59 (Box 646, Folder 7)
- Records, 1959-60 (Box 646, Folder 8)
- Records, 1960-61 (Box 646, Folder 9)
- Records, 1961-62 (Box 646, Folder 10)
- Records, 1962-63 (Box 646, Folder 11)
- Records, 1963-64 (Box 646, Folder 12)
- Records, 1964-65 (Box 646, Folder 13)
- Records, 1965-67 (Box 646, Folder 14)
- Records, 1967-69 (Box 646, Folder 15)
- Records, 1969-73 (Box 646, Folder 16)
- Records, 1973-75 (Box 646, Folder 17)
- Records, 1975-78 (Box 646, Folder 18)
- Photographs, undated (Box 646, Folder 19)
- Newspaper clippings, undated (Box 646, Folder 20)
- Treasurer's Reports, 1967-70 (Box 646, Folder 21)
- 25th Anniversary records, 1977 (Box 646, Folder 22)
- Records, 1975-84 (Box 646.1, Folder 1)
- Records, 1984-87 (Box 646.1, Folder 2)
- Records, 1987-88 (Box 646.1, Folder 3)
- Records, 1988-89 (Box 646.1, Folder 4)
- Records, 1989-90 (Box 646.1, Folder 5)
- Records, 1990-91 (Box 646.1, Folder 6)
- Records, 1991-92 (Box 646.1, Folder 7)
- Records, 1991-92 (Box 646.1, Folder 8)
- Records, 1992-93 (Box 646.1, Folder 9)
- Records, 1992-94 (Box 646.1, Folder 10)
- Records, 1994-95 (Box 646.1, Folder 11)
- Records, 1995-96 (Box 646.1, Folder 12)
- Records, 1996-97 (Box 646.1, Folder 13)
- Records, 1997-98 (Box 646.1, Folder 14)